A Guide to the Papers of Elinor Wylie, 1921-1928
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series II: Correspondence
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "O my darling" [William Rose Benét] "Thursday" [1921 early September], TL, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 1:49)
    "from E. 82nd St., New York City" [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - "N." to "My sweetheart" [William Rose Benét] "Monday, later" [1921 late Summer, early Autumn], TL, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:50)
  - [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling boy" [William Rose Benét] "Wednesday" [1921 late Summer, early Autumn], TL, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 1:51)
  - [Elinor Wylie] to "My good boy" [William Rose Benét] "Saturday" [1921 late Summer, early Autumn], TL, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:52)
    "from 108 E. 82nd St., New York City" [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling boy" [William Rose Benét] "Monday" [1921 early Autumn?], TLS, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 1:53)
    Pencil note bottom of page 2: "R[D] is beautiful - adorable - + as you say, very like you."; "From Florida Ave. A is Alice Parker Hoyt, Henry's wife; S is Robert Shurtleff, who was a friend of both Henry and Alice and who married Alice after Henry's death, though she had left Henry earlier for R.S. FMH is unidentified. Ro is Rosemary Carr Benét, the wife of Stephen Vincent Benét. Alice Hoyt married again in 1920." [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - "E." [Elinor Wylie] to "My dear boy" [William Rose Benét] "Monday" [1921 early Autumn], TLS, 3 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 1:54)
    Autographed note on p. 3. Some minor autographed corrections. "from Florida Ave., Washington, D.C." [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - Elinor [Wylie] to "My dear boy" [William Rose Benét] "Tuesday, Wednesday" [1921 Autumn], TLS, 5 pp. on 5 l. (Box-folder 1:55)
  - "Dmitri" [Elinor Wylie?] to "Pedro my boy" [William Rose Benét] "Wednesday" [1921 Autumn], TL, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:56)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "O darling darling darling" [William Rose Benét] "Thursday" [1921 Autumn], TLS, 3 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 1:57)
  - [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling boy" [William Rose Benét] "Friday" [1921 Autumn], TL, 4 pp. on 4 l. (Box-folder 1:58)
  - [Elinor Wylie] to "Darling boy" [William Rose Benét] "Thursday" [1921 October], TL, 3 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 1:59)
    "about Nets " [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - [Elinor Wylie] to "Darling, darling boy" [William Rose Benét] "Monday" [1921 late Autumn], TL, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 1:60)
    "Henry's book is Dry Point (1921) by her brother Henry Hoyt; Alf is Alfred Harcourt; Miss L is Amy Lovemann; Sara is Sara Teasdale" [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - [Elinor Wylie] to "Darling boy" [William Rose Benét] "Tuesday" [1921 late Autumn], TL, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:61)
    "Leonora Speyer" [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - [Elinor Wylie] to "My most precious darling" [William Rose Benét] [1921 November?], AL, 8 pp. on 6 l. (Box-folder 1:62)
    With transcript by Stanley Olson. "Reginold refers to a lost short story." [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - Elinor Wylie to [William Stanley] Braithwaite 1921 December 20, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:63)
    #8287
  - [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling boy" [William Rose Benét] "Christmas Eve" [1921 December 24], TL, 3 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 1:64)
    Includes two poems: Queer Music. For Harold and Winifred. Xmas 1921. and Christmas Card; "Hal and Winnifred [sic] Wells who lived at 1, University Place, NYC." [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - [Elinor Wylie] to [William Rose Benét] [1921?], TL fragment, 4 pp. on 4 l. (Box-folder 1:65)
    Letter includes Wylie's translation of poem, Adrian's Address to His Soul; Latin version and Lord Byron's translation also included; half of last page of letter carefully removed. "from Washington; Grace is Grace Hegger Lewis, Mrs. Sinclair Lewis" [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - [Elinor Wylie] to "My blessed darling boy" [William Rose Benét] "Saturday" [1922 January or February?], TL, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 1:66)
    "from Washington" [unidentified] #8287-c
  - Dmitri [Elinor Wylie] to "Pete" [William Rose Benét] [1922 Spring, late May], TL, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:67)
    "Dmitri is a character our of a novel by Elinor which became a private name for Bill." [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - [Elinor Wylie] to "My lamb" [William Rose Benét] "Tuesday" [1922 June], TL, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:68)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My very own darlingest boy" [William Rose Benét] "Friday" [1922 early Summer], TL, 5 pp. on 4 l. (Box-folder 1:69)
    Autographed line on verso of page 4: "My love - a [good?] train leaves..." #8287-c
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "Darling, darling boy" [William Rose Benét] "Monday" [1922 Summer], TL, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 1:70)
    "MacDowell" [unidentified] #8287-c
  - [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling love" [William Rose Benét] "Monday" [1922 Summer], TL, 3 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 1:71)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling boy" [William Rose Benét] "Tuesday" [1922 Summer], ALS, 7 pp. on 7 l. (Box-folder 1:72)
    Includes transcription by Stanley Olson. "from MacDowell colony" [unidentified] #8287-c
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling love" [William Rose Benét] "Wednesday" [1922 Summer], TL, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 1:73)
    "from MacDowell" [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My dearest love" [William Rose Benét] "Wednesday" [1922 Summer?], TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:74)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "Darling of my heart" [William Rose Benét] "Wednesday" [1922 Summer], TL, 4 pp. on 4 l. (Box-folder 1:75)
    "MacDowell" [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling, darling boy" [William Rose Benét] "Thursday" [1922 Summer], ALS, 8 pp. on 8 l. (Box-folder 1:76)
    Includes transcription by Stanley Olson. "from MacDowell" [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling" [William Rose Benét] "Thursday" [1922 Summer], TL, 4 pp. on 4 l. (Box-folder 1:77)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "Darling, darling boy" [William Rose Benét] "Friday" [1922 Summer], TL, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 1:78)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My own darling boy" [William Rose Benét] "Saturday morning" [1922 or 1923 Summer], TL, 4 pp. on 4 l. (Box-folder 1:79)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My own adorable angel infant" [William Rose Benét] "Monday" [1922 Summer], TL, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 1:80)
    Letter includes two typed poems, Seven at a Blow, 1 p., and in the body of the letter an untitled poem beginning, "The apple trees bend down with fruit;". [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My own darling" [William Rose Benét] "Monday" [1922 Summer], ALS, 6 pp. on 6 l. (Box-folder 1:81)
    Includes transcription by Stanley Olson. #8287-c
  - [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling" [William Rose Benét] "Tuesday" [1922 Summer?], TL, 3 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 1:82)
  - [Elinor Wylie] to "My dear lamb" [William Rose Benét] "Tuesday" [1922 Summer], TL, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 1:83)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My precious lamb" [William Rose Benét] "Wednesday" [1922 Summer], ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:84)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling love" [William Rose Benét] "Wednesday" [1922 Summer], TL, 3 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 2:1)
    "About Rhode Island divorce from Horace Wylie, which she eventually filed for September 1922 and was later questioned legally" [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling" [William Rose Benét] "Sunday" [1922 Summer], TL, 3 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 2:2)
    "regarding Rhode Island divorce from Horace Wylie which she eventually filed for September, 1922, and was later questioned, legally" [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "Darling boy" [William Rose Benét] "Thursday" [1922 Summer], TL, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:3)
    Penciled note at end of letter: "I love you, darling." "2 September Mama sailed to England" [unidentified] #8287-c
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "Dearest of young animals" [William Rose Benét] "Friday" [1922 Summer], TL, 3 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 2:4)
    "Gene is Eugene Saxton, editor at George Dovan's and later next- door-neighbor at Gramercy Park" [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My own precious boy" [William Rose Benét] ["Friday"?], [1922 Summer], ALS, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling love" [William Rose Benét] "Saturday" [1922 Summer], TLS, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:6)
    " Gerald is Elinor's working title for the novel Jennifer Lorn (1923)." [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "darling lamb" [William Rose Benét] "Saturday" [1922 Summer], ALS, 4 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 2:7)
    Letter includes AMs poem, verso of last page: Oh! let your spirit, like a rainbow shaft...; "Novel is Bill's First Person Singular; Robinson is E. A. Robinson; Mollie and Padraic Collum" [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My own boy" [William Rose Benét] "Tuesday" [1922 August], TL, 3 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 2:8)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "Darling boy" [William Rose Benét] "Friday" [1922 August], TL, 4 pp. on 4 l. (Box-folder 2:9)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My own darling love" [William Rose Benét] "Saturday" [1922 August], TL, 3 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 2:10)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My own darling" [William Rose Benét] "Wednesday" [1922 late Summer], TL, 3 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 2:11)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My heart's delight and angel lamb" [William Rose Benét] "Saturday" [1922 Summer], TL, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:12)
  - [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling lamb" [William Rose Benét] "Monday" [1922 December?], AL, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:13)
  - [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling boy" [William Rose Benét] "Tuesday" [1922 late December?], AL, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:14)
  - [Elinor Wylie] to "Darlingest" [William Rose Benét] "Friday" [1922 late December], AL, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:15)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My own darling" [William Rose Benét] "Tuesday" [1922], TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:16)
    End of letter continued in pen on top of page. #8287-c
  - "N" [Elinor Wylie] to "My own dearest love" [William Rose Benét] "Wednesday" [1922], TL, 6 pp. on 6 l. (Box-folder 2:17)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling love" [William Rose Benét] "Thursday" [ca. 1922], ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:18)
  - [Elinor Wylie] to [William Rose Benét] [ca. 1922?], ALS, 3 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 2:19)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling" [William Rose Benét] "Sunday" [1923 January ?], ALS, 5 pp. on 5 l. (Box-folder 2:20)
    On Vanity Fair letterhead; includes transcription by Stanley Olson. #8287-c
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling love" [William Rose Benét] "Friday" 1923 January 26, ALS, 3 pp. on 3 l., with envelope (Box-folder 2:21)
    On Vanity Fair letterhead. #8287-c
  - "Nell" [Elinor Wylie] to "Darlingest" [William Rose Benét] "Saturday" 1923 January 27, ALS, 5 pp. on 5 l., with envelope (Box-folder 2:22)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling love" [William Rose Benét] "Monday" 1923 January 29, ALS, 7 pp. on 7 l., with envelope (Box-folder 2:23)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My dearest love" [William Rose Benét] "Wednesday" [1923 late January], ALS, 10 pp. on 10 l. (Box-folder 2:24)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling love" [William Rose Benét] "Friday" [1923 late January], ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:25)
    "Bill was ill with influenza in Scarsdale, his parent's home" [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - "Nell" [Elinor Wylie] to "Beloved infant" [William Rose Benét] [1923 January or February?], TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:26)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My dearest love" [William Rose Benét] "Wednesday" [1923 early February], ALS, 8 pp. on 8 l. (Box-folder 2:27)
    On Vanity Fair letterhead. "Bill was ill with influenza in Scarsdale, his parent's home" [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My own darling love" [William Rose Benét] "Tuesday" [1923 February 2], ALS, 6 pp. on 6 l. (Box-folder 2:28)
    On Vanity Fair letterhead; "William Rose Benét's] birthday" [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling love" [William Rose Benét] "Friday" [1923 February 5], ALS, 6 pp. on 6 l., with envelope (Box-folder 2:29)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My precious lamb" [William Rose Benét] [1923] February 6, ALS, 6 pp. on 6 l. (Box-folder 2:30)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling, darling boy" [William Rose Benét] "Thursday" [1923 February 8], ALS, 7 pp. on 7 l. (Box-folder 2:31)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling darling boy" [William Rose Benét] [1923 Spring], ALS, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:32)
    "before E. went to MacDowell Colony 9 June 1923" [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My boy" [William Rose Benét] "Monday" [1923 May or June], TL, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:33)
    On Vanity Fair letterhead; "poem is Primavera of the North published July 1923 in Vanity Fair and later in Last Poems " [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - "E." [Elinor Wylie] to Bill [William Rose Benét] [1923 June], ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:34)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My very dearest love" [William Rose Benét] "Sunday" [1923 June], TL, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:35)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My own darling boy again" [William Rose Benét] "Sunday" [1923 June], TL, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:36)
    Page 1 carefully torn in half; second half missing. #8287-c
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My own darling" [William Rose Benét] "Sunday" [1923 June], TL, 3 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 2:37)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "Darling, darling lamb" [William Rose Benét] "Monday" [1923 June], TL, 3 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 2:38)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My own darling" [William Rose Benét] "Monday" [1923 June], TL, 4 pp. on 4 l. (Box-folder 2:39)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My precious boy" [William Rose Benét] "tuesday" [1923 June], TL, 3 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:40)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My dearest boy" [William Rose Benét] "Thursday" [1923 June], TL, 3 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 2:41)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "O darling of my heart" [William Rose Benét] "Thursday" [1923 June], TL, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:42)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling boy" [William Rose Benét] "Thursday afternoon" [1923 June], TL, 4 pp. on 4 l. (Box-folder 2:43)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling boy" [William Rose Benét] "Friday" [1923 June], TL, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:44)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "Darling, darling lamb" [William Rose Benét] "Saturday" [1923 June], TL, 6 pp. on 6 l. (Box-folder 2:45)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling love" [William Rose Benét] "Thursday" [1923 June 28?], TL, 3 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 2:46)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling darling boy" [William Rose Benét] "Saturday" [1923 June?], ALS, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:47)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My sweetheart" [William Rose Benét] "Sunday" [1923 June?], 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:48)
    Includes poem fragment: This is the stubborn mind that hurries to give...; "from MacDowell" [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My own darling boy" [William Rose Benét] "Monday" [1923 Summer], TL, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:49)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling, more than ever darling boy" [William Rose Benét] "Wednesday" [1923 Summer], TL, 5 pp. on 5 l. (Box-folder 2:50)
    Typed header on letter: "NOTHING BAD ABOUT US: JUST ABOUT MY POOR OLD POEMS, DEAR"; "from MacDowell" [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - [Elinor Wylie] to "Lamb of light" [William Rose Benét] [1923 Summer], TL, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:51)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My dearest love" [William Rose Benét] "Saturday" [1923 Summer], TL, 3 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 2:52)
    "from MacDowell" [unidentified] #8287-c
  - [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling love" [William Rose Benét] [1923 Summer], AL, 4 pp. on 4 l. (Box-folder 2:53)
    Includes transcription by Stanley Olson; "from Easthampton, where her brother Morton and his wife had taken a house." [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My good boy" [William Rose Benét] "Thursday" [1923 July], ALS, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:54)
  - Elinor Wylie to Mr. [Robert] Linscott 1924 March 12, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:55)
    #8287-b
  - Elinor Wylie to James Branch Cabell 1924 October 3, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:56)
    #5947-g
  - Elinor [Wylie] to Grace Hazard Conkling 1925 September 14, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l., with envelope (Box-folder 2:57)
    Includes transcription. #8287
  - Elinor [Wylie] to Grace Hazard Conkling 1925 September 18, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l., with envelope (Box-folder 2:58)
  - Elinor Wylie to [James Branch] Cabell 1926 May 10, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:59)
  - Elinor [Wylie] to Donald Friede 1927 August 30, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l., with envelope (Box-folder 2:60)
  - Elinor [Wylie] Benét to "Dear [Laura]," 1928 February 20, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:61)
    "not her sister-in-law Laura Benét" [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My dear darling boy" [William Rose Benét] "Monday," n.d., ALS, 6 pp on 6 l. (Box-folder 2:62)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "You poor little lamb" [William Rose Benét] "Monday," n.d., ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:63)
    "from 1 University Place, N.Y.C." [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
  - [Elinor Wylie?] to [William Rose Benét?] "Wednesday," n.d., TL, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:64)
  - [Elinor Wylie?] to "My darling lamb" [William Rose Benét] "Thursday afternoon," n.d., AL, 4 pp. on 4 l. (Box-folder 2:65)
    Includes transcription. #8287-c
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My darling" [William Rose Benét] "Saturday," n.d., TL, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:66)
  - "N." [Elinor Wylie] to "My [?]" [William Rose Benét] "Wake-up day," n.d., ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:67)
  - [Elinor Wylie?] to [William Rose Benét?] n.d., TL fragment, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:68)
  - Christmas Cards n.d., 1927, 3 items (Box-folder 2:69)
    "Collection of Christmas Cards in Bill's hand to his Mother and Father" [Stanley Olsen] #8287-c
- Series III: Miscellaneous Clippings and Photographs
  - Newsclippings concerning the death of Elinor Wylie 1928 December 17, 18, 19, Photocopies (Box-folder 2:70)
    #7365
  - Portrait of Elinor Wylie from an unidentified magazine n.d., 1 item (Box-folder 2:71)
    Barrett Prints
  - Photograph of Elinor Wylie 1929 January 3, 1 item (Box-folder 2:72)
    1 8x10 black and white photograph by Nicholas Murray, Barrett Prints